<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on print(&#34;hello!&#34;)</title>
    <link>http://quatl.ooo/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on print(&#34;hello!&#34;)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Avery Lawrence</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 20:41:32 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://quatl.ooo/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using the internet practically</title>
      <link>http://quatl.ooo/posts/internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 20:41:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://quatl.ooo/posts/internet/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post for my friends who are generally tech-literate but not informed about harm reduction online. I will try to update this as my knowledge about the para-internet changes.
The last update was: Feb 20 2023
Browser Firefox is the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; chrome alternative if you care about privacy and not giving alphabet a 90% browser monopoly. Brave is infamously headed by (among other things) a covid denier, Vivaldi is a good power-user browser, and Opera exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motherboards</title>
      <link>http://quatl.ooo/posts/motherboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 18:53:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://quatl.ooo/posts/motherboards/</guid>
      <description>Background Every week I host an open source meetup in Seattle. My friends are always bringing in project laptops to fix up, dual boot linux with, whatever. There&amp;rsquo;s a light-hearted atmosphere, food, people coming and going.
The Problem You can do everything right when e.g. replacing a battery, and end up breaking the motherboard. ASD wristbands and bags, step-by-step manufacturer-supplied teardown instructions, magnetic isolation, the works; the board still undergoes a lot of physical stress in some replacements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gopro</title>
      <link>http://quatl.ooo/posts/gopro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:30 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://quatl.ooo/posts/gopro/</guid>
      <description>Gopro GPS Metadata My startup contract is about to end, so this is a good time for a writeup on the software I wrote to help me do field testing. I should clarify that this wasn&amp;rsquo;t a coding contract; I sought to encounter practical software independently.
In short, we were given gopro cameras to supplement field testing with video, but there was no quantitative positional data accompanying those tests. After poking around, I learned that GoPros do record GPX data (GPS XML), but extract it with either an unsupported 2017 desktop app or a paid phone app that didn&amp;rsquo;t give me files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Font</title>
      <link>http://quatl.ooo/posts/font/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:27:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://quatl.ooo/posts/font/</guid>
      <description>Liberation Mono Surprisingly, the devise theme doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to have a way to change your main font. I forked it and submitted a PR. Soon the site will be less new, and functional enough; I can slow down. I&amp;rsquo;ll write a summary of the gopro metadata project first, because the process was pretty sloppy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aoc22</title>
      <link>http://quatl.ooo/posts/aoc22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 16:52:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://quatl.ooo/posts/aoc22/</guid>
      <description>Background Back in November I told my friends I&amp;rsquo;d do advent of code with them this year. I was going to do it entirely in Rust, because I kept talking about how much I wanted to learn more Rust to actually use it for systems programming. I fell a bit behind, caught up some days, and promised I&amp;rsquo;d catch up when I had more free time over the holidays. String processing was a little weird, but manageable; I spent evenings sipping tea and staring at std::vec::Vec and std::str to replicate the kind of pythonic 10-line algorithms I usually write for leetcode problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipelines</title>
      <link>http://quatl.ooo/posts/pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 14:09:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://quatl.ooo/posts/pipelines/</guid>
      <description>Source to Deploy, directly I had enough free time to throw together this project site over the holidays. Without any real networking knowledge, I snagged on basics for hours; the worst by far1 was the webhooks. Ultimately, the 3 guides I referenced didn&amp;rsquo;t mention that network points and nodes (?) have their own rules for port forwarding:
Cloudflare has a very short whitelist2, Most distros, and particularly webhost distro images (I imagine), require port whitelisting through iptables/nftables backends typically managed with ufw Basically, any point along the source -&amp;gt; browser pipe can block you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://quatl.ooo/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 19:54:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://quatl.ooo/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>it lives and hopefully can document whatever I&amp;rsquo;m working on so I can link my projects &amp;gt;.&amp;lt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
